<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	 xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	 xml:id="user-doc-intro" version="5.0">
  <title>Introduction to the TDF Operating System</title>
  <indexterm><primary>West Virginia University</primary></indexterm>
  <indexterm><primary>tours de force</primary></indexterm>

  <para>
    Welcome to the tours de force version of the MPX Operating System!
    This was created for the Operating Systems course (CS 450) at
    <link xl:href="http://csee.wvu.edu">West Virginia
    University</link> for the Spring 2009 semester. The members of
    tours de force are Tim Bielawa, Andrew Butcher, Jack Dehlin, and
    Bryant Doss. The homepage of tours de force is hosted on <link
    xl:href="http://http://code.google.com/p/tdf-os/">Google
    Code</link>.<footnote><para><link
    xl:href="http://code.google.com/p/tdf-os/"/></para></footnote>
  </para>

  <section>
    <title>About MPX</title>
    <indexterm><primary>James Mooney</primary></indexterm>
    <indexterm><primary>Malcolm Lane</primary></indexterm>

    <para>
      The MPX <indexterm><primary>MPX</primary></indexterm> Operating
      System, which is shorthand for MultiProgramming eXecutive, is a
      project that was created by Malcolm Lane and James Mooney and
      published in the Project Manual of <citetitle pubwork="book">A
      Practical Approach to Operating Systems</citetitle>.
      <footnote><para>A Practical Approach to Operating Systems (1988)
      ISBN: 0-878-35300-3</para></footnote>
    </para>

    <para>
      MPX is programmed using C, and is designed to simulate low-level
      functionality, though it will use an underlying MS-DOS
      installation for hardware abstraction. MPX operates exclusively
      in the command-line interface, and all commands and operations
      will have to be called by a shell.
      <indexterm><primary>MS-DOS</primary></indexterm>
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>About the Command Handler</title>
    <para>
      The command handler is the first interactive piece of TDF which
      you as a user will come into contact with. You can recognize
      when you have reached the command handler by the welcome message
      showing the current version appearing at the top of your
      screen. Below the welcome message will be the command prompt
      waiting for input. What you see will look similar to following.
      <indexterm><primary>command handler</primary></indexterm>
    </para>

    <programlisting>
      Welcome to the Tours de Force System
      tdf-os version: 0.3.33 2009-02-19 (Revision: 95)
      
      <prompt>tdf:$ </prompt>
    </programlisting>
  </section>

</chapter>

