<chapter id="General Description">
  <title>General Description</title>
  
  <section id="Perspective">
    <title>Perspective</title>
    <para>
      The Vorpal Voting System will serve as a polling system to be
      utilized by students of MU. The VVS will integrate with the
      current web based infrastructure maintained by Morgantown
      University.  That being said, VVS will be available via the
      world wide web through the already existing Morgantown
      University web portal.  Students of MU will log into the VVS
      using their credentials assigned by from the university, which
      are on record with the campus admission and records office.
      While the VVS will incorporate with the campus web portal, it
      will be hosted externally on Vorpal Longsword servers and will
      communicate with campus IT to authenticate or verify the status
      of users.
    </para>
    <para>
      The system will be modular enough to house any type of poll;
      Examples include student government elections to campus cafe
      evaluation.  Dynamically, administrators of the system will be
      able to create polls which include an array of options.  Once
      the polls have taken place, statistical results will be sent to
      users and detailed statistics will be available to certain
      users.
    </para>
    <para>
      The basis of the system lies in the roles of users which will be
      provided by the system.  This includes the actual student users
      (SV's), student organization and government officials (PA's),
      faculty advisors / university provost (VVSA's).  Certain
      privileges will are provided depending on the user in question.
      The privileges are detailed in the diagrams included in this
      section.  It is assumed that the privileges available to the SV
      are available to the PA, which are in turn available to the VVSA
      with slight variation.
    </para>
    
    <section id="Context Diagram">
      <title>Context Diagram</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata fileref="CD_VVS.jpg" />
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </section>
    
    <section id="Use Case Diagram">
      <title>Use Case Diagram</title>
      <mediaobject>
	<imageobject>
	  <imagedata fileref="UseCaseDiagram.jpg" />
	</imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </section>
  </section>
  
  <section id="System Evolution">
    <title>System Evolution</title>
    <para>
      This is the system evolution section.
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="Product Functions">
    <title>Product Functions</title>
    <para>
      This is the product functions section.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>General Functions</title>
      
      <section>
	<title>Login</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a user to login to the VVS and verifies their credentials.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Logout</title>
	<para>
	  Logs the user out of the VVS.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Student Voting Functions</title>
      <section>
	<title>Poll_display_available</title>
	<para>
	  Displays a list of all polls in which an SV is eligible to cast a vote.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Poll_select_to_vote</title>
	<para>
	  Selects the poll for which an SV wants to vote.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Vote</title>
	<para>
	  Allows the SV to cast a vote.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Administrator Poll Creation Functions</title>
      
      <section>
	<title>Ballot_create</title>
	<para>
	  Allows the PA to create a new custom ballot or to load a previously saved ballot template.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Ballot_delete</title>
	<para>
	  Allows the PA to delete a ballot if it has not yet been confirmed.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Ballot_modify</title>
	<para>
	  Allows the PA to modify a ballot if it has not yet been confirmed.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Ballot_save_changes</title>
	<para>
	  Saves all changes that have been made to a ballot.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Ballot_confirm</title>
	<para>
	  Shows all ballot information and allows the PA to cancel, modify or confirm. Once confirm is selected, no more changes may be made to the ballot.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Results and Statistical Viewing Functions</title>
      
      <section>
	<title>Result_statistic_select_report</title>
	<para>
	  Allows user to select the type of report they want to see.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Result_statistic_select_poll</title>
	<para>
	  Allows the user to select the poll(s) they wish to see in a report.
	</para>
      </section>
      
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Administrative Functions</title>
      
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_database_sync</title>
	<para>
	  The VVS connects with the Admissions and Records student information database and updates the VVS SDF with any changes. Makes appropriate changes to voter groups.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_database_add_voter</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to add a SV to the VVS SDF.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_database_delete_voter</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a SV to the VVS SDF. Makes appropriate changes to voter groups.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_database_modify_voter</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to modify a SV’s information in the VVS SDF.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_poll_administrator_create</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to create a new PA and set their usage privileges.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_poll_administrator_delete</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a PA.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_poll_administrator_modify</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to modify a PA’s information or usage privileges.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrator_poll_template_create</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to create a ballot template that can be used by PA’s when they create a ballot.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrator_poll_template_delete</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a ballot template.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_poll_template_modify</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to modify a ballot template.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_voter_group_create</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to create a new voter group by selecting SV’s and/or selecting previously saved voter groups.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_voter_group_delete</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a voter group.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrative_voter_group_modify</title>
	<para>
	  Allows a VVS Administrator to modify the members of a voter group.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="User Characteristics">
    <title>User Characteristics</title>
    <para>
      The following are users within Morgantown University as
      specified by the scope of the VVS.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>Student Body (SV)</title>
      <para>
	College level students with minimal understanding of
	university systems and technical knowledge. Students log into
	the system and place their votes.  When polls end, they get an
	email notification if they participated in the poll.  Will be
	the main users of the system.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Student Organization Representatives or Officials (PA)</title>
      <para>
	College students/leaders who will be the main administrators
	of the system. They have the final say on the visual layout
	"look and feel" of the individual polls created.  PA's get
	access to detailed statistical breakdowns of the polls they
	create, with respect to anonymous voter demographics.  These
	users also appear as students when it comes to actually voting
	within the system, but have access to "behind the stage"
	functionality. Limited access and technical knowledge to
	school systems.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Faculty Advisor (VVSA)</title>
      <para>
	Professors or professionals employed by the university to
	cooperate with student government and organizations which may
	possess a low level of technical knowledge.  These users will
	be responsible for creating and removing student PA's to the
	voting system.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>University Provost (VVSA)</title>
      <para>
	Individual in charge of creating VVSA's, that is specifying
	other faculty members which are capable of working with
	student organizations and government to administer for the
	system.  These users may possess minimal technical knowledge.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>University IT</title>
      <para>
	University employees who manage the servers, databases,
	etc. High levels of technical understanding. Will work
	closely with in order to verify students records
	(cooperating with Admissions and Records) and to work in
	concert with the already evident campus web portal.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  
  <section id="General Constraints">
    <title>General Constraints</title>
    <section id="Regulatory Policies">
      <title>Regulatory Policies</title>
      <para>
	Data collected by the VVS from SVs shall remain anonymous at
	all times. Polling results collected by the VVS will only be
	released after the lifetime of a poll has passed and a PA has
	selected to release the results. Released data will only be
	displayed through units of percentages, e.g.: percentage of
	voters who selected each poll option.
      </para>
      <para>
	To maintain poll data integrity, only student voters whose
	identity and voting elegability has been confirmed by the VVS
	with the VVS database on a pollwise status, as well as with
	the Admissions and Records database by means of the Campus IT
	systems will be granted access to any given poll.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="Hardware Limitations">
      <title>Hardware Limitations</title>
      <para>
	The VVS will run on the hardware that has been approved by the
	Campus IT department. The minimal hardware requirements of the
	interface by which SVs interact with the VVS will be an
	internet enabled laptop or desktop. The SV interface will run
	on all student authorized internet accessable computers that
	Morgantown University maintains. The SV interface to the VVS
	will require a dial up modem internet connection speed or
	greater.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="Interfaces to Other Applications">
      <title>Interfaces to other Applications</title>
      <para>
	The VVS will communicate with the Campus IT computer systems
	through an encrypted connection protocol.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="Parallel Operations">
      <title>Parallel Operations</title>
      <para>
	The user authentication process depends on other system taks
	completing before it can complete. These systems are said to
	be working in parallel.
      </para>
      <para>
	At the initiation of any new session all individuals
	attempting to gain access to the VVS will be required to
	present their authentication credentials over a secured
	communication channel. When the users supplied credentials
	have been collected by the VVS a query is made over a secure
	channel from the VVS through Campus IT which asks if the
	supplied information matches what Admissions and Records
	maintains for that user.
      </para>
      <para>
	When Campus IT has recieved a response from the Admissions and
	Records systems the response is relayed back to the VVS. When
	these communications have been received operation returns to
	handling the authenticating users session.
      </para>
      <para>
	To the authenticating user this appears as one operation,
	though it is actually multiple processes running concurrently.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="Language Specifications">
      <title>Language Specifications</title>
      <para>
	The VVS will be available through an English language
	interface.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="Reliability Requirements">
      <title>Reliability Requirements</title>
      <para>
	The reliability of the VVS is defined as "always available."
	This is subject to the availability of the Campus IT Systems.
	Currently Campus IT Systems are only available from 00:00 on
	Monday to 23:59 Saturday. Given those limitations the VVS will
	only be available for use from 00:00 Monday through 23:59
	Saturday.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  
  <section id="Assumptions and Dependencies">
    <title>Assumptions and Dependencies</title>
    <para>
      The following are assumptions and dependencies which are evident
      in the system:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	The system will be packaged in such a way that it will be
	deployable on any server with an existing database.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	Students utilizing the system will be able to access the from
	any computer which has access to the internet.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	The system will provide sufficient training to new users as
	well as administrators of the system regardless of their
	technology skill level.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	The system will be available any time the campus web portal is
	available.  The campus web portal is sometimes down on
	Sundays, which means that authentication will be reliant on
	the maintenance of the campus web portal.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	VVS will comply with all conventions relevant to polling.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	Polls will only be accessible within the time frame specified
	by the administrator.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	Polls will not be available for editing by anyone, regardless
	of status, during the active poll time period specified by the
	administrator.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	Statistics will be served depending on the wishes of the poll
	creator.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	There will be no vulnerabilities in the system where
	information will be available to outsiders to the system.
	Users will remain anonymous.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para>
      The following will cover how risks will be assessed in the
      system:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	Testing will take place in which student
	organization/government officials, faculty advisors, and the
	university provost will be involved to ensure the completeness
	in functionality of the system.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	Students voters will be able to provide their opinions
	regarding system performance after the initial release of the
	system.
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	Security measures will be in place to ensure the integrity of
	the system and protect the anonymity of the student users.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>
</chapter>
