<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <title>Vorpal Voting System</title>
  <bookinfo>
    <subtitle>Requirements Definition</subtitle>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
	<personname>
	  <surname>Bielawa</surname>
	  <firstname>Timothy</firstname>
	  <othername>"Shaggy"</othername>
	</personname>
      </author>
      <author>
	<personname>
	  <surname>Butcher</surname>
	  <firstname>Andrew</firstname>
	</personname>
      </author>
      <author>
	<personname>
	  <surname>Carpenter</surname>
	  <firstname>Ben</firstname>
	</personname>
      </author>
      <author>
	<personname>
	  <surname>Connell</surname>
	  <firstname>Jonathan</firstname>
	</personname>
      </author>
      <author>
	<personname>
	  <surname>Justice</surname>
	  <firstname>Joshua</firstname>
	</personname>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
    <revhistory>
      <revision>
	<revnumber>0.1</revnumber>
	<date>2008/10/14</date>
	<revremark>First Draft</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>
  </bookinfo>

  <chapter>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    
    <section>
      <title>Purpose</title>
      <para>
	To give a detailed description of the Vorpal Voting System to
	include all functions and requirements specified by Morgantown
	University and its representatives. These representatives
	include the University Provost, student groups and their
	advisor, the student body representative(s), Admissions and
	Records, and the Office of Information Technology (OIT). This
	document is also intended to give a clear and concise summary
	of all communication between Vorpal Longsword +1 (known herein
	as the developer) and all Morgantown University
	Representatives (known herein as the stakeholders) which
	pertains to the required functions and uses of the Vorpal
	Voting System.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Scope</title>
      <para>
	The stakeholders have determined they require all elections
	and polls that apply to the student body to be handled and
	maintained through an interactive online system. The developer
	has created the Vorpal Voting System (VVS) as a solution to
	this software need.
      </para>
      <para>
	The VVS will allow university student groups to create and
	manage their own elections and polls online. The VVS will also
	allow all eligible students to vote in elections and polls
	online. Students will be able to access the VVS through their
	University’s Web Portal that is already in place. All results
	and statistical data resulting from elections and polls will
	be maintained by the VVS for 7 years. The VVS will interface
	directly with Admissions and Records databases to create its
	own database of all eligible student voters which, once
	created, will be accessible independent of the Admission and
	Records databases. Finally, the VVS will conform to all
	general election standards unless otherwise specified
	within. The VVS will be used strictly for election and polling
	purposes only. The VVS will not be used in any manner which
	provides support or facilitates election campaigning. It will
	also not be used to host elections that only apply to
	University faculty or administrators.
      </para>
      <para>
	Once the VVS is installed and operational it will drastically
	improve the timeliness and efficiency of student oriented
	elections and polls. The system should encourage and increase
	voter participation by making it easier for students to
	vote. Students will be able to vote from any computer with an
	internet connection. Results will be available immediately
	following the close of any election and statistical data will
	be available for use by the stakeholders.
      </para>
      <para>
	It is the goal of the developer to create a system that has a
	user friendly interface and meets all of the requirements and
	functionality requested by the stakeholders.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Definititions and Abbreviations</title>
      <para>
	<emphasis>MU</emphasis> - Morgantown University.      
      </para>
      <para>
	<emphasis>VVS</emphasis> - Vorpal Voting System, the interactive
	online system that will be used for elections and polls by the
	stakeholders.
      </para>
      <para>
	Developer Vorpal Longsword +1, the company that will create
	and install the VVS. The developer is also responsible for
	training University personnel in the use and maintenance of
	the VVS.
      </para>
      <para>
	Administrator, a person with elevated privileges compared to
	general users. They have access to the "behind the curtain"
	functionality of the Vorpal Voting System. Also referred to as
	"super users".
      </para>
      <para>
	<emphasis>PA</emphasis> - Poll Administrator, a person who has
	access to poll creation and results within the VVS.
      </para>
      <para>
	<emphasis>SDF</emphasis> - Student Database File, a list of all
	students and their personal information that will be used by
	the VVS to determine whether a student is eligible to vote in
	a particular election or poll. The SDF will be populated
	primarily by the VSS interfacing with Admissions and Records,
	but VVS administrators will also be able to add, delete, or
	modify entries in the SDF.
      </para>
      <para>
	Stakeholders, All of the Morgantown University Representatives
	mentioned in section 1.1 of this document
      </para>
      <para>
	<emphasis>SV</emphasis> - Student Voter, a registered student of Morgantown
	University that is eligible to participate in a particular
	election or poll.
      </para>
      <para>
	<emphasis>VVSA</emphasis> - Vorpal Voting System Administrator, a person who has
	access to all the functions of the VVS and is responsible for
	maintaining the system and assigning PAs as needed by
	Morgantown University
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>References</title>
      <para>
	IEEE Std 830-1998 IEEE Recommended Practice for Software
	Requirements Specifications – Description
      </para>
      <para>
	Pressman, Rodger. Software Engineering: A Practitioner’s
	Approach. 6th Edition. New York. McGraw Hill, 2005.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <para>
	The rest of this document will focus on the design process and
	the functionality of the VVS. The document will be used by
	both the developer and stakeholders to ensure that the needs
	of the stakeholder are being met while the VVS is under
	development. Hardware and interfaces with other systems will
	be explained. The methods and procedures the developer will
	use to produce the VVS will be discussed in detail. All
	functions of the system will be listed with a brief
	explanation. Detailed explanation of functionality will be
	discussed in future documentation. A description of possible
	users and their level of technical proficiency as relating to
	the use of the system will be covered. Constraints of the
	system will be discussed and finally a brief risk assessment
	and evaluation of assumptions and dependencies will be
	included.
      </para>
    </section>
    
  </chapter>
  
  <chapter>
    <title>General Description</title>
    
    <section>
      <title>Perspective</title>
      <para>
	The Vorpal Voting System will serve as a polling system to be
	utilized by students of MU. The VVS will integrate with the
	current web based infrastructure maintained by Morgantown
	University.  That being said, VVS will be available via the
	world wide web through the already existing Morgantown
	University web portal.  Students of MU will log into the VVS
	using their credentials assigned by from the university, which
	are on record with the campus admission and records office.
	While the VVS will incorporate with the campus web portal, it
	will be hosted externally on Vorpal Longsword servers and will
	communicate with campus IT to authenticate or verify the
	status of users.
      </para>
      <para>
	The system will be modular enough to house any type of poll;
	Examples include student government elections to campus cafe
	evaluation.  Dynamically, administrators of the system will be
	able to create polls which include an array of options.  Once
	the polls have taken place, statistical results will be sent
	to users and detailed statistics will be available to certain
	users.
      </para>
      <para>
	The basis of the system lies in the roles of users which will
	be provided by the system.  This includes the actual student
	users (SV's), student organization and government officials
	(PA's), faculty advisors / university provost (VVSA's).
	Certain privileges will are provided depending on the user in
	question.  The privileges are detailed in the diagrams
	included in this section.  It is assumed that the privileges
	available to the SV are available to the PA, which are in turn
	available to the VVSA with slight variation.
      </para>
      
      <section>
	<title>Context Diagram</title>
	<mediaobject>
	  <imageobject>
	    <imagedata fileref="CD_VVS.jpg" scale="85"/>
	  </imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Use Case Diagram</title>
	<mediaobject>
	  <imageobject>
	    <imagedata fileref="UseCaseDiagram.jpg" />
	  </imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>System Evolution</title>
      
      <section>
	<title>Life Cycle Model</title>
	<para>
	  Throughout the design of the VVS, development was done using
	  a 'Waterfall with Prototyping' model.  By using this model,
	  the customer will have the opportunity to view a prototype
	  of the VVS throught its design process.  This will allow the
	  developer to retrieve feedback from the customer so as to be
	  able to adjust the prototype to conform to the customer's
	  liking as much as possible.  Once a prototype is established
	  that the customer and developer both agree upon actual code
	  writing can begin.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Training</title>
	<para>
	  Training for the provost, faculty advisors, and student
	  government representatives will need to occur before they
	  can be expected to manage the VVS.  Due to the fact that the
	  Provost will ultimately be the one to choose who has
	  administrator rights as either a VVSA or a PA, training will
	  need to occur whenever a new administrator is chosen.  Once
	  the Provost chooses an initial round of VVSAs, those VVSAs
	  will be trained by our group as to how to manage the VVS, as
	  well as how to train future VVSAs and PAs.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Installation</title>
	<para>
	  The system installation for the VVS will be done as an
	  abrupt cut-over during the coming summer.  To the end user
	  the new system should be very straightforward, so an abrupt
	  cut-over from the previous system should not confuse any
	  users.  By doing this, the old voting system will now be
	  obsolete and unneccessary.  Because there really will not be
	  any remnants of the old voting method being used, developers
	  will have to be very sure that the VVS is error-free.  This
	  will be done by means of very thorough testing.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Product Functions</title>
      <para>
	
      </para>
      <section>
	<title>General Functions</title>
	
	<section>
	  <title>Login</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a user to login to the VVS and verifies their
	    credentials.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Logout</title>
	  <para>
	    Logs the user out of the VVS.
	  </para>
	</section>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Student Voting Functions</title>
	<section>
	  <title>Poll_display_available</title>
	  <para>
	    Displays a list of all polls in which an SV is eligible to
	    cast a vote.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Poll_select_to_vote</title>
	  <para>
	    Selects the poll for which an SV wants to vote.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Vote</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows the SV to cast a vote.
	  </para>
	</section>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Administrator Poll Creation Functions</title>
	
	<section>
	  <title>Ballot_create</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows the PA to create a new custom ballot or to load a
	    previously saved ballot template.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Ballot_delete</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows the PA to delete a ballot if it has not yet been
	    confirmed.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Ballot_modify</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows the PA to modify a ballot if it has not yet been
	    confirmed.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Ballot_save_changes</title>
	  <para>
	    Saves all changes that have been made to a ballot.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Ballot_confirm</title>
	  <para>
	    Shows all ballot information and allows the PA to cancel,
	    modify or confirm. Once confirm is selected, no more
	    changes may be made to the ballot.
	  </para>
	</section>
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Results and Statistical Viewing Functions</title>
	
	<section>
	  <title>Result_statistic_select_report</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows user to select the type of report they want to see.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Result_statistic_select_poll</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows the user to select the poll(s) they wish to see in
	    a report.
	  </para>
	</section>
	
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Administrative Functions</title>
	
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_database_sync</title>
	  <para>
	    The VVS connects with the Admissions and Records student
	    information database and updates the VVS SDF with any
	    changes. Makes appropriate changes to voter groups.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_database_add_voter</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to add a SV to the VVS SDF.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_database_delete_voter</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a SV to the VVS
	    SDF. Makes appropriate changes to voter groups.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_database_modify_voter</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to modify a SV’s information in
	    the VVS SDF.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_poll_administrator_create</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to create a new PA and set
	    their usage privileges.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_poll_administrator_delete</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a PA.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_poll_administrator_modify</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to modify a PA’s information or
	    usage privileges.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrator_poll_template_create</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to create a ballot template
	    that can be used by PA’s when they create a ballot.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrator_poll_template_delete</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a ballot template.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_poll_template_modify</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to modify a ballot template.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_voter_group_create</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to create a new voter group by
	    selecting SV’s and/or selecting previously saved voter
	    groups.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_voter_group_delete</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to delete a voter group.
	  </para>
	</section>
	<section>
	  <title>Administrative_voter_group_modify</title>
	  <para>
	    Allows a VVS Administrator to modify the members of a
	    voter group.
	  </para>
	</section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>User Characteristics</title>
      <para>
	The following are users within Morgantown University as
	specified by the scope of the VVS.
      </para>
      <section>
	<title>Student Body (SV)</title>
	<para>
	  College level students with minimal understanding of
	  university systems and technical knowledge. Students log
	  into the system and place their votes.  When polls end, they
	  get an email notification if they participated in the poll.
	  Will be the main users of the system.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Student Organization Representatives or Officials (PA)</title>
	<para>
	  College students/leaders who will be the main administrators
	  of the system. They have the final say on the visual layout
	  "look and feel" of the individual polls created.  PA's get
	  access to detailed statistical breakdowns of the polls they
	  create, with respect to anonymous voter demographics.  These
	  users also appear as students when it comes to actually
	  voting within the system, but have access to "behind the
	  stage" functionality. Limited access and technical knowledge
	  to school systems.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Faculty Advisor (VVSA)</title>
	<para>
	  Professors or professionals employed by the university to
	  cooperate with student government and organizations which
	  may possess a low level of technical knowledge.  These users
	  will be responsible for creating and removing student PA's
	  to the voting system.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>University Provost (VVSA)</title>
	<para>
	  Individual in charge of creating VVSA's, that is specifying
	  other faculty members which are capable of working with
	  student organizations and government to administer for the
	  system.  These users may possess minimal technical
	  knowledge.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>University IT</title>
	<para>
	  University employees who manage the servers, databases,
	  etc. High levels of technical understanding. Will work
	  closely with in order to verify students records
	  (cooperating with Admissions and Records) and to work in
	  concert with the already evident campus web portal.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>General Constraints</title>
      <section>
	<title>Regulatory Policies</title>
	<para>
	  Data collected by the VVS from SVs shall remain anonymous at
	  all times. Polling results collected by the VVS will only be
	  released after the lifetime of a poll has passed and a PA
	  has selected to release the results. Released data will only
	  be displayed through units of percentages, e.g.: percentage
	  of voters who selected each poll option.
	</para>
	<para>
	  To maintain poll data integrity, only student voters whose
	  identity and voting elegability has been confirmed by the
	  VVS with the VVS database on a pollwise status, as well as
	  with the Admissions and Records database by means of the
	  Campus IT systems will be granted access to any given poll.
	</para>
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Hardware Limitations</title>
	<para>
	  The VVS will run on the hardware that has been approved by
	  the Campus IT department. The minimal hardware requirements
	  of the interface by which SVs interact with the VVS will be
	  an internet enabled laptop or desktop. The SV interface will
	  run on all student authorized internet accessable computers
	  that Morgantown University maintains. The SV interface to
	  the VVS will require a dial up modem internet connection
	  speed or greater.
	</para>
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Interfaces to other Applications</title>
	<para>
	  The VVS will communicate with the Campus IT computer systems
	  through an encrypted connection protocol.
	</para>
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Parallel Operations</title>
	<para>
	  The user authentication process depends on other system taks
	  completing before it can complete. These systems are said to
	  be working in parallel.
	</para>
	<para>
	  At the initiation of any new session all individuals
	  attempting to gain access to the VVS will be required to
	  present their authentication credentials over a secured
	  communication channel. When the users supplied credentials
	  have been collected by the VVS a query is made over a secure
	  channel from the VVS through Campus IT which asks if the
	  supplied information matches what Admissions and Records
	  maintains for that user.
	</para>
	<para>
	  When Campus IT has recieved a response from the Admissions
	  and Records systems the response is relayed back to the
	  VVS. When these communications have been received operation
	  returns to handling the authenticating users session.
	</para>
	<para>
	  To the authenticating user this appears as one operation,
	  though it is actually multiple processes running
	  concurrently.
	</para>
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Language Specifications</title>
	<para>
	  The VVS will be available through an English language
	  interface.
	</para>
      </section>
      
      <section>
	<title>Reliability Requirements</title>
	<para>
	  The reliability of the VVS is defined as "always available."
	  This is subject to the availability of the Campus IT
	  Systems.  Currently Campus IT Systems are only available
	  from 00:00 on Monday to 23:59 Saturday. Given those
	  limitations the VVS will only be available for use from
	  00:00 Monday through 23:59 Saturday.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Assumptions and Dependencies</title>
      <para>
	The following are assumptions and dependencies which are
	evident in the system:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    The system will be packaged in such a way that it will be
	    deployable on any server with an existing database.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Students utilizing the system will be able to access the
	    from any computer which has access to the internet.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    The system will provide sufficient training to new users
	    as well as administrators of the system regardless of
	    their technology skill level.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    The system will be available any time the campus web
	    portal is available.  The campus web portal is sometimes
	    down on Sundays, which means that authentication will be
	    reliant on the maintenance of the campus web portal.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    VVS will comply with all conventions relevant to polling.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Polls will only be accessible within the time frame
	    specified by the administrator.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Polls will not be available for editing by anyone,
	    regardless of status, during the active poll time period
	    specified by the administrator.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Statistics will be served depending on the wishes of the
	    poll creator.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    There will be no vulnerabilities in the system where
	    information will be available to outsiders to the system.
	    Users will remain anonymous.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      
      <para>
	The following will cover how risks will be assessed in the
	system:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Testing will take place in which student
	    organization/government officials, faculty advisors, and
	    the university provost will be involved to ensure the
	    completeness in functionality of the system.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Students voters will be able to provide their opinions
	    regarding system performance after the initial release of
	    the system.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Security measures will be in place to ensure the integrity
	    of the system and protect the anonymity of the student
	    users.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>
