<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Commands Summary</title>
  <para>
    This chapter is to serve as a summary of the basic commands that
    are implemented in the TDF operating system. For a more detailed
    description of the commands, please refer to the Detailed Commands
    Information chapter in this manual, or employ the "help" command
    in the operating system environment.
  </para>

  <section>
    <title>date</title>
    <para>
      Displays the system date.  When given an optional -s option
      followed by a valid date string in the format YYYYMMDD, the date
      will be set to the specified date.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>display</title>
    <para>
      Displays the contents of the current working directory, which is
      all of the files with an extension of <filename>.MPX</filename>.
      Optionally accepts a relative or absolute directory path to
      function on.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>exit</title>
    <para>
      The exit command will terminate the MPX operating system. There
      are no additional arguments that may be passed to this
      command. This is the safest way to end your MPX session. You
      will be prompted for confirmation before you are dropped.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>help</title>
    <para>
      The help command will print out a list of commands and a brief
      description of each. This is a very useful command to those
      unfamiliar with the system. For help on a specific command,
      simple type the name of the command you would like help with as
      the argument.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>history</title>
    <para>
      The history command will print out a list of the user's previous
      commands.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>presume</title>
    <para>
      The presume command returns a process from the suspended
      state. To return a process from the suspended state to the ready
      state run presume with the name of the process as the argument.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>psetprio</title>
    <para>
      The psetprio command is used to set the priority of a
      process. The priority must be within the -128 to 127 or an error
      will be returned.  To set the priority of a process run psetprio
      with an argument -n for the name of the process and argument -p
      for the priority.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>pshow</title>
    <para>
      The pshow command displays pertinent information about a
      particular process. To display information for a process run
      pshow with the name of the desired process as the argument.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>pshowall</title>
    <para>
      The pshowall command displays information on all of the current
      processes regardless of their states. To display information on
      all current processes run pshowall with no arguments.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>pshowblk</title>
    <para>
      The pshowblk command displays information on all processes
      currently in the blocked state. To display information on all
      currently blocked processes run pshowblk with no arguments.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>pshowrd</title>
    <para>
      The pshowrd command displays information on all processes
      currently in in the ready state. To display information on all
      currently ready processes run pshowrd with no arguments.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>psuspend</title>
    <para>
      The psuspend command places a process in the suspended state. To
      place a process in the suspended state run psuspend with the
      name of the process as the argument.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>version</title>
    <para>
      The version command will print out the current version,
      including the version number, date of release, and the first
      several digits of the subversion commit, which is the source
      control for tours de force.
    </para>
  </section>

</chapter>
