<chapter id="Overview of Source Files and Directories">
  <title>Overview of Source Files and Directories</title>
  <para>
    This chapter is designed to provide an overview of each file and
    directory of the project. Hopefully, it will provide a good idea of how
    the source of TDF-OS is layed out.
  </para>
 
  <itemizedlist>

    <listitem>
      <formalpara>
	<title>build</title>
        <para>
	  The build directory is reserved for compiled source files of
	  TDF-OS.
        </para>
	</formalpara>
      </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <formalpara>
	<title>doc</title>
        <para>
	  The doc directory contains the various XML files for the DocBook
	  style documentation.
          <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      devel - contains developer documentation
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      user - contains the user's manual
	    </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara>
      </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <formalpara>
	<title>src</title>
	<para>
	  The src directory contains all of the C source files as well as the
	  header files. Each file located in the src directory has a
	  corresponding header file located in the src/include.
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      DATE.C - contains the date command for the shell
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      DISPLAY.C - contains the display command for the shell
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      HELP.C - contains the help command for the shell
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      HISTORY.C - contains the history command for the shell
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      MPX_SUPT.C - Dr. Mooney's support file for MPX
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      PARSER.C - parses the input buffer of the shell
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      PCB.C - contains all internal structures and functions for PCBs
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      PCBMAKE.C - contains pcreate and pdelete shell commands
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      PCBMAN.C - contains pblock, presume, punblock, psuspend, and
	      psetprio shell commands
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      PCBSHOW.C - contains pshow, pshowall, pshowrd, and pshowblk
	      shell commands
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      PCBUTILS.C - contains various functions that are useful when
	      working with PCBs
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      SHELL.C - contains the main driver for the TDF shell
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      TDF.C - the initializer module
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      TDF.CFG - contains compiler information in TurboC
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      TDF.PRJ - used to link the project together in TurboC
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
	      VERSION.C - contains the version command in the shell
            </listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	</para>
      </formalpara>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <formalpara>
	<title>target</title>
        <para>
          The target directory is reserved for the created executable file.
	  This is where the operating system is run, and thus some .MPX
	  files are put there during build time for demonstration.
        </para>
	</formalpara>
      </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <formalpara>
	<title>tc</title>
        <para>
	  The tc directory is reserved for containing the TurboC compiler, 
	  which is required for the MPX operating system.
          <itemizedlist>
          </itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara>
      </listitem>


    <listitem>
      <formalpara>
	<title>utils</title>
        <para>
	  The utils directory contains various configuration files for making
	  the developers' lives easier, including build scripts and 
	  configration files for DOSBox. These typically should not be
	  adjusted and do not affect the source at all.
        </para>
	</formalpara>
      </listitem>

  </itemizedlist>
      <para>
	Finally, there is the Makefile which will pull the build scripts
	together for easy development.
      </para>
      

</chapter>
