<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>Commands Summary</title>
  <para>
    This chapter is to serve as a summary of the temporary commands that
    are implemented in the TDF operating system. For a more detailed
    description of the commands, please refer to the Detailed Commands
    Information chapter in this manual, or employ the "help" command
    in the operating system environment.
  </para>

  <section>
    <title>pcreate</title>
    <para>
      The pcreate command is used to create processes. to create a process
      run pcreate with a name for the process as the argument. Once pcreate
      has been run, if a valid process name is given, the user must input
      the priority, state, and class for the process. The priority must
      be in the range -128 to 127. The state must be in the range 0 to 3
      indication states ready, blocked, ready-suspended, and blocked-suspended
      respectively. The class must be either a 0 or 1 indicating application
      or system process respectively. 
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>pdelete</title>
    <para>
      The pdelete command is used to completely delete a process, remove it
      from all queues and free its memory. To delete a process run pdelete
      with the name of the intended process as the argument.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>pblock</title>
    <para>
      The pblock command is used to place a process in the blocked state.
      If the process is in the ready state when pblock is invoked on it
      it will be placed in the blocked state. If the process is in the suspended
      state when pblock is run on it it will be placed in the blocked-suspended
      state. The place a process in the blocked or blocked-suspended state
      run pblock with the name of the process as the argument.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>punblock</title>
    <para>
      The punblock command is used to remove a process from a blocked state.
      If the process is in the blocked state when punblock is invoked then it 
      will be returned to the ready state. If the process is in the 
      blocked-suspended state when punblock is invoked then it will be placed
      in the suspended state. To unblock a process run punblock with the name
      of the process as the argument.
    </para>
  </section>

</chapter>
